https://www.auburn.edu/main/privacy.php

Skip to Navigation Skip to Content
Privacy Statements
Primary Privacy Statement
Auburn University (the "University," "we") respects the privacy of individuals who use its websites. We are committed to ensuring the privacy and security of your sensitive and confidential information provided to the University online.
Please note that many units of the University run and maintain their own websites on the auburn.edu domain.
These sites may provide additional notices about the information they collect related to your web browsing experience, which may supplement this Privacy Statement. By visiting auburn.edu you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this notice.
What Information We Collect
Our web servers, like all webservers, collect information such as the IP address of your computer, the operating system, browser software used, access times, and pages visited.
This data is used statistically and in aggregate to monitor web server performance, network security and to help manage the site and improve service.
Auburn University does not track individual visitor profiles but does reserve the right to use log data to diagnose problems with our server or networks, analyze resource management or investigate security concerns.
Some of our webpages may link to external websites not owned or controlled by the University. The University is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites.
What Information We Collect
Most pages on the auburn.edu domain utilize a technology known as Google Analytics that allows us to gather general statistics regarding how our websites are used. For example, if we know what browser software and screen resolution our users are utilizing, we are better able to design web pages that suit our users.
The statistics we generate are aggregate.
We do not track the usage patterns of individual users, in fact, we use Google Analytics anonymization to prevent Google's ability to cross-reference your use on our site with data collected on other sites utilizing their services. Please visit the Google Analytics website for more information.
Cookies
A cookie is a small file placed onto your device that enables features and functionality. The information contained in a cookie typically includes information collected automatically by the web server and/or information provided voluntarily by the user. Google Analytics uses cookies to generate statistics about out site.
Auburn University policy does not allow the release of personally identifiable information to third parties (other than its agents when required for university business) without the permission of the person identified, or as allowed or required by law. We do not sell the information we collect from individual visitors to our websites to third parties.
Other Data Collection
Visitors using online forms or applications on our web pages may choose to supply information voluntarily. Information collected via such web forms will be securely maintained and be used only for the purposes for which it was supplied. Pages collecting such information should be transparent about the information they are collecting as well as the purpose for the data collection.
Auburn University policy does not allow the release of personally identifiable information to third parties (other than its agents when required for university business) without the permission of the person identified, or as allowed or required by law. We do not sell the information we collect from individual visitors to our websites to third parties.
Information Protection
The University implements reasonable physical, technical and administrative safeguards designed to prevent unauthorized access to or use of the information we collect online. While we strive to protect your information, we cannot guarantee or warrant the security of such electronic data. However, we will only use your information for the educational, research, or other purpose in furtherance of the University's mission for which it was provided.
Your information will be retained or disposed of according to the University's records management principles and polices.
Individual Rights of the Data Subject under the GDPR
In addition to the right to receive the information provided in this Privacy Notice, if you are an individual data subjects covered by under GDPR you have the right to:
Request from Auburn University access to and rectification or erasure of Personal Data or restriction of processing concerning the Data Subject, the right to object to processing and the right to portability of Personal Data;
Where processing is based upon consent, to withdraw consent at any time, without affecting Auburn University's right to process Personal Data based upon consent before its withdrawal;
The right to file a complaint with a supervisory authority appointed by an EU member state for the purpose of receiving complaints;
Additional notice of the existence of automated decision-making, including profiling;
If the Personal Data is going to be further processed for a purpose other than that for which it was collected, then notice of the purpose and basis or bases for the further processing;
If Personal Data is collected for Auburn University's legitimate interests or for a task carried out in the public interest, then the Data Subject has the right to object, on the grounds of his or her particular situation, to the processing of Personal Data concerning him or her (including profiling);
Where Personal Data are processed for direct marketing purposes, the right to object at any time to processing Personal Data concerning him or her for such marketing; and
Not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling, which produces legal effects concerning him or her or similarly significantly affects him or her; provided, however, that this right does not apply if the decision is (a) necessary for entering into, or performance of, a contract between the Data Subject and Auburn University; or (b) is based upon the Data Subject's consent.
Note: Exercising these rights guarantees access to a process but does not guarantee any particular outcome.
Any Data Subject who wishes to exercise any of the above-mentioned rights may do so by filing such request with the designated Data Protection Officer:
Director of Institutional Compliance & Privacy
Office of Audit, Compliance & Privacy
304 Samford Hall, Auburn University, AL 36849
(334) 844-4389
Changes to this Policy
This Privacy Policy may be amended from time to time. Any such changes will be posted on this page. Your continued usage of the site indicates your acceptance of such changes.
Last updated 1/24/20.
Privacy Statement: Admissions & Enrollment Services
This Privacy Notice outlines the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Data provided to Auburn University ("AU") by prospective undergraduate and graduate students and applicants.
Additionally, this document provides notice as required under the European Union's ("EU") General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR"), which regulates data collection and use of Personal Data of persons located in the EU.
For purposes of this notice, Personal Data includes such information as name, email address, physical address, photos, IP address, as well as other sensitive personal data obtained with prior consent.
Lawful Basis for Collecting and Processing Personal Data
AU is an institution of higher education involved in education, research, and public service. In order for AU to educate its students both in person and electronically, engage in research, and provide public service, it is essential, necessary, and AU has lawful bases to collect, process, use, and maintain data of its students, employees, applicants, research subjects, and others involved in its educational, research, and public service programs. The lawful bases include, without limitation, admission, registration, delivery of classroom, on-line, and study abroad education, grades, communications, employment, applied research, development, program analysis for improvements, and records retention.
Most of AU's collection and processing of Personal Data will fall under the following categories:
Processing that is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by AU or third parties in providing education, employment, research and development, and public service.
Processing that is necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is party or in order to take steps at the request of the data subject prior to entering into a contract.
Processing that is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which AU is subject.
Processing for which the data subject has given consent for AU to use his or her personal data for one or more specific purposes.
There will be some instances where the collection and processing of personal data will be pursuant to other lawful bases.
Types of Personal Data Collected/Processed and Purpose
Enrollment Services and the Graduate School collect the following categories of Personal Data in order to recruit and admit undergraduate and graduate students:
Name
Contact information including, without limitation, email address, physical address, phone number, and other location data
Unique personal identifiers and biographical information (e.g. date of birth)
Details of your educational qualifications
Information related to visa requirements, copies of passports and other documents to ensure compliance with U.S. laws
Financial information gathered for the purposes of verifying eligibility for study in the United States
Information related to the prevention and detection of crime and the safety of employees, students and visitors of Auburn University
The Personal Data that Enrollment Services and the Graduate School collect may be shared internally with academic units, Alumni Affairs and other school officials with a legitimate educational interest.
If you have specific questions regarding the collection and use of your Personal Data by Enrollment Services, please contact the Director, Enrollment Services-Operations at (334) 844-6420. For questions regarding the collection and use of your Personal Data by the Graduate School, please contact the Dean of the Graduate School at (334) 844-4700.
If you refuse to provide Personal Data that Auburn University required in connection with one of Auburn University's lawful bases for collecting such Personal Data, such refusal may make it impossible for Auburn University to provide you education, employment, research or other requested services.
Where Auburn University gets Personal and Sensitive Personal Data
Auburn University receives Personal Data from multiple sources. Most often, Auburn University gets this data directly from the Data Subject or under the direction of the Data Subject who has provided it to a third party. In addition to data collected from the Data Subject, Enrollment Services and the Graduate School may collect data from ACT, College Board, Cappex, ETS, and the State of Alabama Statewide Transfer & Articulation Reporting System (STARS) and other entities in accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA).
Individual Rights of the Data Subject under the GDPR
In addition to the right to receive the information provided in this Privacy Notice, if you are an individual data subject covered by GDPR (i.e. located in the EU/EEA) you have the right to:
Request from Auburn University access to and rectification or erasure of Personal Data or restriction of processing Personal Data concerning the Data Subject, the right to object to processing and the right to portability of Personal Data;
Where processing is based upon consent, to withdraw consent at any time, without affecting Auburn University's right to process Personal Data based upon consent before its withdrawal;
The right to file a complaint with a supervisory authority appointed by an EU member state for the purpose of receiving complaints;
Additional notice of the existence of automated decision-making, including profiling;
If the Personal Data is going to be further processed for a purpose other than that for which it was collected, then notice of the purpose and basis or bases for the further processing;
If Personal Data is collected for Auburn University's legitimate interests or for a task carried out in the public interest, then the Data Subject has the right to object, on the grounds of his or her particular situation, to the processing of Personal Data concerning him or her (including profiling);
Where Personal Data are processed for direct marketing purposes, the right to object at any time to processing Personal Data concerning him or her for such marketing; and
Not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling, which produces legal effects concerning him or her or similarly significantly affects him or her; provided, however, that this right does not apply if the decision is (a) necessary for entering into, or performance of, a contract between the Data Subject and Auburn University; or (b) is based upon the Data Subject's consent.
Note: Exercising these rights guarantees access to a process but does not guarantee any particular outcome.
Any Data Subject who wishes to exercise any of the above-mentioned rights may do so by filing such request with the designated Data Protection Officer:Director of Institutional Compliance & Privacy
Office of Audit, Compliance & Privacy 304 Samford Hall, Auburn University, AL 36849 (334) 844-4389
Cookies
Cookies are files that many websites transfer to users' web browsers to enable the site to deliver personalized services or to provide persistent authentication. The information contained in a cookie typically includes information collected automatically by the web server and/or information provided voluntarily by the user. Auburn University's websites use persistent cookies in conjunction with a third party technology partner to analyze search engine usage and web traffic patterns. This information is used in the aggregate to monitor and enhance our web pages. It is not used to track the usage patterns of individual users. For more information see our main website Privacy Statement.
Security of Personal Data
All Personal Data and sensitive Personal Data collected or processed by Auburn University must comply with the security controls and systems and process requirements and standards set forth in Auburn University's Policies Database as they are amended from time-to-time. Auburn University will not share your Personal Data with third parties except:
as necessary to meet one of its lawful purposes, including but not limited to, its legitimate interest, contract compliance, pursuant to consent provided by the Data Subject, or as required or authorized by law;
as necessary to protect Auburn University's interests;
with service providers acting on Auburn University's behalf who have agreed to protect the confidentiality of the Personal Data.
Data Retention
Auburn University maintains records for the time periods specified in the Public Universities of Alabama - Functional Analysis & Records Disposition Authority.
Privacy Statement: Office of Audit, Compliance & Privacy
This Privacy Notice outlines the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Data provided to the Auburn University ("AU") Office of Audit, Compliance & Privacy ("OACP") by non-AU subscribers to Case in Point: Lessons for the proactive manager.
Additionally, this document provides notice as required under the European Union's ("EU") General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR") which regulates data collection and use of Personal Data of persons located in the EU.
For purposes of this notice, Personal Data includes such information as name, email address, physical address, photos, IP address, as well as other sensitive personal data obtained with prior consent.
Lawful Basis for Collecting and Processing Personal Data
AU is an institution of higher education involved in education, research, and public service. In order for AU to educate its students both in person and electronically, engage in research, and provide public service, it is essential, necessary, and AU has lawful bases to collect, process, use, and maintain data of its students, employees, applicants, research subjects, and others involved in its educational, research, and public service programs. The lawful bases include, without limitation, admission, registration, delivery of classroom, on-line, and study abroad education, grades, communications, employment, applied research, development, program analysis for improvements, and records retention.
Most of AU's collection and processing of Personal Data will fall under the following categories:
Processing that is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by AU or third parties in providing education, employment, research and development, and public service.
Processing that is necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is party or in order to take steps at the request of the data subject prior to entering into a contract.
Processing that is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which AU is subject.
Processing for which the data subject has given consent for AU to use his or her personal data for one or more specific purposes.
There will be some instances where the collection and processing of personal data will be pursuant to other lawful bases.
Types of Personal Data Collected/Processed and Purpose
OACP collects the following categories of Personal Data, with your consent, in order to fulfil external (non-AU) requests to be added to our monthly newsletter ("Case in Point: Lessons for the proactive manager"):
Your email address
The following information is requested but you may choose not to provide it:
Your Name
Your job title
Your place of employment
The Personal Data that OACP collects as part of this subscription process will be saved to our service provider's (Constant Contact) databases in order to manage our subscription lists and facilitate the sending of our newsletter.
We may also share your information among OACP management in order to evaluate and improve our subscription reach. If you have specific questions regarding the collection and use of your Personal Data by OACP, please contact the Robert Gottesman, Director Institutional Compliance & Privacy at 334.844.4389 If you refuse to provide your email address it will be impossible for OACP to provide you with a subscription to our newsletter: Case In Point. Access to newsletter content may still be obtained via our website.
Where Auburn University gets Personal and Sensitive Personal Data
Auburn University OACP receives personal and sensitive Personal Data, for the purpose of sending our newsletter from the data subject directly from the Data Subject or under the direction of the Data Subject who has provided it to a third party.
Individual Rights of the Data Subject under the GDPR
In addition to the right to receive the information provided in this Privacy Notice, if you are an individual data subject covered by under GDPR (i.e. located in the EU/EEA) you have the right to:
Request from Auburn University access to and rectification or erasure of Personal Data or restriction of processing Personal Data concerning the Data Subject, the right to object to processing and the right to portability of Personal Data;
Where processing is based upon consent, to withdraw consent at any time, without affecting Auburn University's right to process Personal Data based upon consent before its withdrawal;
The right to file a complaint with a supervisory authority appointed by an EU member state for the purpose of receiving complaints;
Additional notice of the existence of automated decision-making, including profiling;
If the Personal Data is going to be further processed for a purpose other than that for which it was collected, then notice of the purpose and basis or bases for the further processing;
If Personal Data is collected for Auburn University's legitimate interests or for a task carried out in the public interest, then the Data Subject has the right to object, on the grounds of his or her particular situation, to the processing of Personal Data concerning him or her (including profiling);
Where Personal Data are processed for direct marketing purposes, the right to object at any time to processing Personal Data concerning him or her for such marketing; and
Not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling, which produces legal effects concerning him or her or similarly significantly affects him or her; provided, however, that this right does not apply if the decision is (a) necessary for entering into, or performance of, a contract between the Data Subject and Auburn University; or (b) is based upon the Data Subject's consent.
Note: Exercising these rights guarantees access to a process but does not guarantee any particular outcome.
Any Data Subject who wishes to exercise any of the above-mentioned rights may do so by filing such request with the designated Data Protection Officer:Director of Institutional Compliance & Privacy
Office of Audit, Compliance & Privacy 304 Samford Hall, Auburn University, AL 36849 (334) 844-4389
Cookies
Cookies are files that many websites transfer to users' web browsers to enable the site to deliver personalized services or to provide persistent authentication. The information contained in a cookie typically includes information collected automatically by the web server and/or information provided voluntarily by the user. Auburn University's websites use persistent cookies in conjunction with a third party technology partner to analyze search engine usage and web traffic patterns. This information is used in the aggregate to monitor and enhance our web pages. It is not used to track the usage patterns of individual users. For more information see our main website Privacy Statement.
Security of Personal Data
All Personal Data and sensitive Personal Data collected or processed by Auburn University must comply with the security controls and systems and process requirements and standards set forth in Auburn University's Policies Database as they are amended from time-to-time. Auburn University will not share your Personal Data with third parties except:
as necessary to meet one of its lawful purposes, including but not limited to, its legitimate interest, contract compliance, pursuant to consent provided by the Data Subject, or as required or authorized by law;
as necessary to protect Auburn University's interests;
with service providers acting on Auburn University's behalf who have agreed to protect the confidentiality of the Personal Data.
Data Retention
Auburn University maintains records for the time periods specified in the Public Universities of Alabama - Functional Analysis & Records Disposition Authority.
Privacy Statement: Human Resources Employees
This Privacy Notice outlines the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Data provided to Auburn University ("AU") by EMPLOYEES.  Additionally, this document provides notice as required under the European Union's ("EU") General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR"), which regulates data collection and use of Personal Data of persons located in the EU.
For purposes of this notice, Personal Data includes such information as name, email address, physical address, photos, IP address, as well as other sensitive personal data obtained with prior consent.
Lawful Basis for Collecting and Processing Personal Data
AU is an institution of higher education involved in education, research, and public service. In order for AU to educate its students both in person and electronically, engage in research, and provide public service, it is essential, necessary, and AU has lawful bases to collect, process, use, and maintain data of its students, employees, applicants, research subjects, and others involved in its educational, research, and public service programs. The lawful bases include, without limitation, admission, registration, delivery of classroom, on-line, and study abroad education, grades, communications, employment, applied research, development, program analysis for improvements, and records retention.
Most of AU's collection and processing of Personal Data will fall under the following categories:
Processing that is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by AU or third parties in providing education, employment, research and development, and public service.
Processing that is necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is party or in order to take steps at the request of the data subject prior to entering into a contract.
Processing that is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which AU is subject.
Processing for which the data subject has given consent for AU to use his or her personal data for one or more specific purposes.
There will be some instances where the collection and processing of personal data will be pursuant to other lawful bases.
Types of Personal Data Collected/Processed and Purpose
Human Resources collects the following categories of Personal Data in order to establish and maintain an employment relationship in compliance with federal and state laws, as well as Auburn University policies and benefit programs.
Name
Contact information including, without limitation, email address, physical address, phone number, and other location data
Unique personal identifiers and biographical information (e.g. date of birth)
Details of your education and/or employment qualifications
Information related to visa requirements, copies of passports and other documents to ensure compliance with U.S. laws
Information of dependents for benefit plan administration
Contact information including, email address, physical address, phone number, and other location data of personal references for employment purposes.
Financial information gathered for the purposes of verifying eligibility for study in the United States
Information related to the prevention and detection of crime and the safety of employees, students and visitors of Auburn University
The Personal Data that HUMAN RESOURCES collects may be shared with:
Human resource administration internally for in the facilitation of resource related policies and processes to include (e.g. payroll, leave), organizational management, benefit administration, compensation management, professional development, performance management, as well as any employment related correspondence.
Companies or organizations providing specific services to, or on behalf of, the University, such as criminal, sex offender, driving and education background checks (background checks are conducted as a condition of employment)
Federal and/or State regulatory agencies
Any relevant professional or state agency or organization
Third parties the University has contracted with to assist with benefits administration, onboarding processes, performance management and/or other related HR services
Court officials to adhere to court mandates or legal obligations
Internal and external organizations to produce statistics and research for internal and statutory/regulatory reporting purposes
Agencies and trusted advisers in order to receive professional advice or guidance in relation to a number of matters (e.g. legal and audit services, fee status verification) or to provide services to you through a third party on our behalf
our online directory
Other than as set out above, we will not normally publish or disclose any personal information about you to other external enquirers or organizations unless you have requested it or consented to it, we are legally obligated to do so, or unless it is in your vital interest (e.g. in an emergency situation)
If you have specific questions regarding the collection and use of your Personal Data by HUMAN RESOURCES, please contact the Marketing and Communication Specialist, 1550 East Glen Avenue, Auburn, AL 36830 or (334) 844-4145. If you refuse to provide Personal Data that Auburn University required in connection with one of Auburn University's lawful bases for collecting such Personal Data, such refusal may make it impossible for Auburn University to provide you education, employment, research or other requested services.
Where Auburn University gets Personal and Sensitive Personal Data
Auburn University receives Personal Data from multiple sources. Most often, Auburn University gets this data directly from the Data Subject or under the direction of the Data Subject who has provided it to a third party. In addition to data collected from the Data Subject, Human Resources collects data from:
Third parties the University partners with to assist in benefits administration, background check facilitation and in the management of Auburn University policies and procedures
Individual Rights of the Data Subject under the GDPR
In addition to the right to receive the information provided in this Privacy Notice, if you are an individual data subject covered by under GDPR (i.e. located in the EU/EEA) you have the right to:
Request from Auburn University access to and rectification or erasure of Personal Data or restriction of processing Personal Data concerning the Data Subject, the right to object to processing and the right to portability of Personal Data;
Where processing is based upon consent, to withdraw consent at any time, without affecting Auburn University's right to process Personal Data based upon consent before its withdrawal;
The right to file a complaint with a supervisory authority appointed by an EU member state for the purpose of receiving complaints;
Additional notice of the existence of automated decision-making, including profiling;
If the Personal Data is going to be further processed for a purpose other than that for which it was collected, then notice of the purpose and basis or bases for the further processing;
If Personal Data is collected for Auburn University's legitimate interests or for a task carried out in the public interest, then the Data Subject has the right to object, on the grounds of his or her particular situation, to the processing of Personal Data concerning him or her (including profiling);
Where Personal Data are processed for direct marketing purposes, the right to object at any time to processing Personal Data concerning him or her for such marketing; and
Not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling, which produces legal effects concerning him or her or similarly significantly affects him or her; provided, however, that this right does not apply if the decision is (a) necessary for entering into, or performance of, a contract between the Data Subject and Auburn University; or (b) is based upon the Data Subject's consent.
Note: Exercising these rights guarantees access to a process but does not guarantee any particular outcome.
Any Data Subject who wishes to exercise any of the above-mentioned rights may do so by filing such request with the designated Data Protection Officer:Director of Institutional Compliance & Privacy
Office of Audit, Compliance & Privacy 304 Samford Hall, Auburn University, AL 36849 (334) 844-4389
Cookies
Cookies are files that many websites transfer to users' web browsers to enable the site to deliver personalized services or to provide persistent authentication. The information contained in a cookie typically includes information collected automatically by the web server and/or information provided voluntarily by the user. Auburn University's websites use persistent cookies in conjunction with a third party technology partner to analyze search engine usage and web traffic patterns. This information is used in the aggregate to monitor and enhance our web pages. It is not used to track the usage patterns of individual users. For more information see our main website Privacy Statement.
Security of Personal Data
All Personal Data and sensitive Personal Data collected or processed by Auburn University must comply with the security controls and systems and process requirements and standards set forth in Auburn University's Policies Database as they are amended from time-to-time.
Auburn University will not share your Personal Data with third parties except:
as necessary to meet one of its lawful purposes, including but not limited to, its legitimate interest, contract compliance, pursuant to consent provided by the Data Subject, or as required or authorized by law;
as necessary to protect Auburn University's interests;
with service providers acting on Auburn University's behalf who have agreed to protect the confidentiality of the Personal Data.
Data Retention
Auburn University maintains records for the time periods specified in the Public Universities of Alabama - Functional Analysis & Records Disposition Authority.
Privacy Statement: Employment Applicants
This Privacy Notice outlines the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Data provided to Auburn University ("AU") by Employee Applicant(s).
Additionally, this document provides notice as required under the European Union's ("EU") General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR"), which regulates data collection and use of Personal Data of persons located in the EU.
For purposes of this notice, Personal Data includes such information as name, email address, physical address, photos, IP address, as well as other sensitive personal data obtained with prior consent.
Lawful Basis for Collecting and Processing Personal Data
AU is an institution of higher education involved in education, research, and public service. In order for AU to educate its students both in person and electronically, engage in research, and provide public service, it is essential, necessary, and AU has lawful bases to collect, process, use, and maintain data of its students, employees, applicants, research subjects, and others involved in its educational, research, and public service programs. The lawful bases include, without limitation, admission, registration, delivery of classroom, on-line, and study abroad education, grades, communications, employment, applied research, development, program analysis for improvements, and records retention.
Most of AU's collection and processing of Personal Data will fall under the following categories:
Processing that is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by AU or third parties in providing education, employment, research and development, and public service.
Processing that is necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is party or in order to take steps at the request of the data subject prior to entering into a contract.
Processing that is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which AU is subject.
Processing for which the data subject has given consent for AU to use his or her personal data for one or more specific purposes.
There will be some instances where the collection and processing of personal data will be pursuant to other lawful bases.
Types of Personal Data Collected/Processed and Purpose
Human Resources collects the following categories of Personal Data in order to process information necessary for recruitment and selection decisions or necessary for compliance with a legal obligation:
Name
Contact information including, without limitation, email address, physical address, phone number, and other location data
Unique personal identifiers and biographical information (e.g. date of birth)
Details of your education and/or employment qualifications
Information related to visa requirements, copies of passports and other documents to ensure compliance with U.S. laws
Information related to the prevention and detection of crime and the safety of employees, students and visitors of Auburn University
Contact information including, without limitation, email address, physical address, phone number, and other location data of personal and professional references (provided on application materials)
The Personal Data that AU collects may be shared on an as needed basis with:
Appropriate employees at the University during recruitment and selection processes
Professional and personal references provided on application materials
Companies or organizations providing specific services to, or on behalf of, the University for recruitment and selection purposes to include, criminal, driving and academic background checks (background checks are conducted as a condition of employment)
Appropriate government agencies
If you have specific questions regarding the collection and use of your Personal Data collected as part of non-faculty employment application by Human Resources, please contact the Marketing and Communication Specialist, 1550 East Glen Avenue, Auburn, AL 36830 or (334) 844-4145, for questions about the data collected as part of a faculty employee application please contact the Special Assistant to the Provost for Human Resources, 208 Samford Hall, Auburn, AL 36849 or (334) 844-4000.
If you refuse to provide Personal Data that Auburn University required in connection with one of Auburn University's lawful bases for collecting such Personal Data, such refusal may make it impossible for Auburn University to provide you education, employment, research or other requested services.
Where Auburn University gets Personal and Sensitive Personal Data
Auburn University receives Personal Data from multiple sources. Most often, Auburn University gets this data directly from the Data Subject or under the direction of the Data Subject who has provided it to a third party. In addition to data collected from the Data Subject, AU collects data from
Companies or organizations providing specific services to, or on behalf of, the University for recruitment and selection purposes to include, criminal, driving and academic background checks
Individual Rights of the Data Subject under the GDPR
In addition to the right to receive the information provided in this Privacy Notice, if you are an individual data subject covered under GDPR (i.e. located in the EU/EEA) you have the right to:
Request from Auburn University access to and rectification or erasure of Personal Data or restriction of processing Personal Data concerning the Data Subject, the right to object to processing and the right to portability of Personal Data;
Where processing is based upon consent, to withdraw consent at any time, without affecting Auburn University's right to process Personal Data based upon consent before its withdrawal;
The right to file a complaint with a supervisory authority appointed by an EU member state for the purpose of receiving complaints;
Additional notice of the existence of automated decision-making, including profiling;
If the Personal Data is going to be further processed for a purpose other than that for which it was collected, then notice of the purpose and basis or bases for the further processing;
If Personal Data is collected for Auburn University's legitimate interests or for a task carried out in the public interest, then the Data Subject has the right to object, on the grounds of his or her particular situation, to the processing of Personal Data concerning him or her (including profiling);
Where Personal Data are processed for direct marketing purposes, the right to object at any time to processing Personal Data concerning him or her for such marketing; and
Not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling, which produces legal effects concerning him or her or similarly significantly affects him or her; provided, however, that this right does not apply if the decision is (a) necessary for entering into, or performance of, a contract between the Data Subject and Auburn University; or (b) is based upon the Data Subject's consent.
Note: Exercising these rights guarantees access to a process but does not guarantee any particular outcome.
Any Data Subject who wishes to exercise any of the above-mentioned rights may do so by filing such request with the designated Data Protection Officer:Director of Institutional Compliance & Privacy
Office of Audit, Compliance & Privacy 304 Samford Hall, Auburn University, AL 36849 (334) 844-4389
Cookies
Cookies are files that many websites transfer to users' web browsers to enable the site to deliver personalized services or to provide persistent authentication. The information contained in a cookie typically includes information collected automatically by the web server and/or information provided voluntarily by the user. Auburn University's websites use persistent cookies in conjunction with a third party technology partner to analyze search engine usage and web traffic patterns. This information is used in the aggregate to monitor and enhance our web pages. It is not used to track the usage patterns of individual users. For more information see our main website Privacy Statement.
Security of Personal Data
All Personal Data and sensitive Personal Data collected or processed by Auburn University must comply with the security controls and systems and process requirements and standards set forth in Auburn University's Policies Database as they are amended from time-to-time.
Auburn University will not share your Personal Data with third parties except:
as necessary to meet one of its lawful purposes, including but not limited to, its legitimate interest, contract compliance, pursuant to consent provided by the Data Subject, or as required or authorized by law;
as necessary to protect Auburn University's interests;
with service providers acting on Auburn University's behalf who have agreed to protect the confidentiality of the Personal Data.
Data Retention
Auburn University maintains records for the time periods specified in the Public Universities of Alabama - Functional Analysis & Records Disposition Authority.
Privacy Statement: Office of Registrar — Students
This Privacy Notice outlines the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Data provided to Auburn University ("AU") by current or former students.  Additionally, this document provides notice as required under the European Union's ("EU") General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR"), which regulates data collection and use of Personal Data of persons located in the EU.
For purposes of this notice, Personal Data includes such information as name, email address, physical address, photos, IP address, as well as other sensitive personal data obtained with prior consent.
Lawful Basis for Collecting and Processing Personal Data
AU is an institution of higher education involved in education, research, and public service. In order for AU to educate its students both in person and electronically, engage in research, and provide public service, it is essential, necessary, and AU has lawful bases to collect, process, use, and maintain data of its students, employees, applicants, research subjects, and others involved in its educational, research, and public service programs. The lawful bases include, without limitation, admission, registration, delivery of classroom, on-line, and study abroad education, grades, communications, employment, applied research, development, program analysis for improvements, and records retention.
Most of AU's collection and processing of Personal Data will fall under the following categories:
Processing that is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by AU or third parties in providing education, employment, research and development, and public service.
Processing that is necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is party or in order to take steps at the request of the data subject prior to entering into a contract.
Processing that is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which AU is subject.
Processing for which the data subject has given consent for AU to use his or her personal data for one or more specific purposes.
There will be some instances where the collection and processing of personal data will be pursuant to other lawful bases.
Types of Personal Data Collected/Processed and Purpose
The Office of the Registrar collects the following categories of Personal Data in order to maintain the accuracy of student records:
Name
Contact information including, without limitation, email address, physical address, phone number, and other location data
Unique personal identifiers and biographical information (e.g. date of birth)
Details of your education
Information related to visa requirements, copies of passports and other documents to ensure compliance with U.S. laws
Information related to the prevention and detection of crime and the safety of employees, students and visitors of Auburn University
The Personal Data that the Office of the Registrar collects may be shared with other school officials with a legitimate educational interest. In the interest of complying with Federal and State legal requirements, as well as performing services for the institution, Personal Data may be shared with third party partners, vendors, accreditors, and agencies, including but not limited to, the Alabama Commission of Higher Education, the National Student Clearinghouse, and the State of Alabama and other entities in accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA).
If you have specific questions regarding the collection and use of your Personal Data by the Office of the Registrar, please contact the University Registrar at registrar@auburn.edu.
If you refuse to provide Personal Data that Auburn University required in connection with one of Auburn University's lawful bases for collecting such Personal Data, such refusal may make it impossible for Auburn University to provide you education, employment, research or other requested services.
Where Auburn University gets Personal and Sensitive Personal Data
Auburn University receives Personal Data from multiple sources. Most often, Auburn University gets this data directly from the Data Subject or under the direction of the Data Subject who has provided it to a third party. In addition to data collected from the Data Subject, the Office of the Registrar collects receives data from other educational institutions.
Individual Rights of the Data Subject under the GDPR
In addition to the right to receive the information provided in this Privacy Notice, if you are an individual data subject covered by under GDPR (i.e. located in the EU/EEA) you have the right to:
Request from Auburn University access to and rectification or erasure of Personal Data or restriction of processing Personal Data concerning the Data Subject, the right to object to processing and the right to portability of Personal Data;
Where processing is based upon consent, to withdraw consent at any time, without affecting Auburn University's right to process Personal Data based upon consent before its withdrawal;
The right to file a complaint with a supervisory authority appointed by an EU member state for the purpose of receiving complaints;
Additional notice of the existence of automated decision-making, including profiling;
If the Personal Data is going to be further processed for a purpose other than that for which it was collected, then notice of the purpose and basis or bases for the further processing;
If Personal Data is collected for Auburn University's legitimate interests or for a task carried out in the public interest, then the Data Subject has the right to object, on the grounds of his or her particular situation, to the processing of Personal Data concerning him or her (including profiling);
Where Personal Data are processed for direct marketing purposes, the right to object at any time to processing Personal Data concerning him or her for such marketing; and
Not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling, which produces legal effects concerning him or her or similarly significantly affects him or her; provided, however, that this right does not apply if the decision is (a) necessary for entering into, or performance of, a contract between the Data Subject and Auburn University; or (b) is based upon the Data Subject's consent.
Note: Exercising these rights guarantees access to a process but does not guarantee any particular outcome.
Any Data Subject who wishes to exercise any of the above-mentioned rights may do so by filing such request with the designated Data Protection Officer:Director of Institutional Compliance & Privacy
Office of Audit, Compliance & Privacy 304 Samford Hall, Auburn University, AL 36849 (334) 844-4389
Cookies
Cookies are files that many websites transfer to users' web browsers to enable the site to deliver personalized services or to provide persistent authentication. The information contained in a cookie typically includes information collected automatically by the web server and/or information provided voluntarily by the user. Auburn University's websites use persistent cookies in conjunction with a third party technology partner to analyze search engine usage and web traffic patterns. This information is used in the aggregate to monitor and enhance our web pages. It is not used to track the usage patterns of individual users. For more information see our main website Privacy Statement.
Security of Personal Data
All Personal Data and sensitive Personal Data collected or processed by Auburn University must comply with the security controls and systems and process requirements and standards set forth in Auburn University's Policies Database as they are amended from time-to-time.
Auburn University will not share your Personal Data with third parties except:
as necessary to meet one of its lawful purposes, including but not limited to, its legitimate interest, contract compliance, pursuant to consent provided by the Data Subject, or as required or authorized by law;
as necessary to protect Auburn University's interests;
with service providers acting on Auburn University's behalf who have agreed to protect the confidentiality of the Personal Data.
Data Retention
Auburn University maintains records for the time periods specified in the Public Universities of Alabama - Functional Analysis & Records Disposition Authority.
Privacy Statement: Office of International Programs
This Privacy Notice outlines the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Data provided to the Auburn University ("AU") Office of International Programs by prospective students, students, former students, potential visiting scholars, visiting scholars, potential employees and employees.  Additionally, this document provides notice as required under the European Union's ("EU") General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR"), which regulates data collection and use of Personal Data of persons located in the EU.
For purposes of this notice, Personal Data includes such information as name, email address, physical address, photos, IP address, as well as other sensitive personal data obtained with prior consent.
Lawful Basis for Collecting and Processing Personal Data
AU is an institution of higher education involved in education, research, and public service. In order for AU to educate its students both in person and electronically, engage in research, and provide public service, it is essential, necessary, and AU has lawful bases to collect, process, use, and maintain data of its students, employees, applicants, research subjects, and others involved in its educational, research, and public service programs. The lawful bases include, without limitation, admission, registration, delivery of classroom, on-line, and study abroad education, grades, communications, employment, applied research, development, program analysis for improvements, and records retention.
Most of AU's collection and processing of Personal Data will fall under the following categories:
Processing that is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by AU or third parties in providing education, employment, research and development, and public service.
Processing that is necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is party or in order to take steps at the request of the data subject prior to entering into a contract.
Processing that is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which AU is subject.
Processing for which the data subject has given consent for AU to use his or her personal data for one or more specific purposes.
There will be some instances where the collection and processing of personal data will be pursuant to other lawful bases.
Types of Personal Data Collected/Processed and Purpose
The Office of International Programs collects the following categories of Personal Data in order to process immigration documentation as required by the U.S. government; to enroll students in study abroad and/or exchange programs; and/or to facilitate and coordinate emergency assistance for AU students and personnel on AU programs/business abroad:
Name
Contact information including, without limitation, email address, physical address, phone number, other location data and emergency contact information
Unique personal identifiers and biographical information (e.g. date and place of birth)
Dependent information if dependents are accompanying the Data Subject during travel abroad and/or to the U.S.
Details of your education and/or employment qualifications
Information related to visa requirements, copies of passports and other documents to ensure compliance with U.S. laws
Financial information gathered for the purposes of verifying eligibility for study in the United States
Information related to the prevention and detection of crime and the safety of employees, students and visitors of Auburn University
The Personal Data that the Office of International Programs collects may be shared with AU departments including Admissions, the Office of the Registrar, the Office of Risk Management, the Office of Campus Safety and Security, the Graduate School, Student Financial Services, academic and administrative departments, Human Resources and Housing; and with external organizations such as the Department of Homeland Security, Customs and Border Patrol, the U.S. Department of State, U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services, the Veterans Administration, Alabama Secretary of State and PACT offices, Auburn Global, insurance companies contracted to serve AU students and personnel in emergencies overseas. This information may also be stored in software licensed by AU for the purposes stated above.
If you have specific questions regarding the collection and use of your Personal Data by the Office of International Programs, please contact the assistant provost for international programs at intledu@auburn.edu.
If you refuse to provide Personal Data that Auburn University required in connection with one of Auburn University's lawful bases for collecting such Personal Data, such refusal may make it impossible for Auburn University to provide you education, employment, research or other requested services.
Where Auburn University gets Personal and Sensitive Personal Data
Auburn University receives Personal Data from multiple sources. Most often, Auburn University gets this data directly from the Data Subject or under the direction of the Data Subject who has provided it to a third party. In addition to data collected from the Data Subject, the Office of International Programs collects data from Auburn Global.
Individual Rights of the Data Subject under the GDPR
In addition to the right to receive the information provided in this Privacy Notice, if you are an individual data subject covered by under GDPR (i.e. located in the EU/EEA) you have the right to:
Request from Auburn University access to and rectification or erasure of Personal Data or restriction of processing Personal Data concerning the Data Subject, the right to object to processing and the right to portability of Personal Data;
Where processing is based upon consent, to withdraw consent at any time, without affecting Auburn University's right to process Personal Data based upon consent before its withdrawal;
The right to file a complaint with a supervisory authority appointed by an EU member state for the purpose of receiving complaints;
Additional notice of the existence of automated decision-making, including profiling;
If the Personal Data is going to be further processed for a purpose other than that for which it was collected, then notice of the purpose and basis or bases for the further processing;
If Personal Data is collected for Auburn University's legitimate interests or for a task carried out in the public interest, then the Data Subject has the right to object, on the grounds of his or her particular situation, to the processing of Personal Data concerning him or her (including profiling);
Where Personal Data are processed for direct marketing purposes, the right to object at any time to processing Personal Data concerning him or her for such marketing; and
Not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling, which produces legal effects concerning him or her or similarly significantly affects him or her; provided, however, that this right does not apply if the decision is (a) necessary for entering into, or performance of, a contract between the Data Subject and Auburn University; or (b) is based upon the Data Subject's consent.
Note: Exercising these rights guarantees access to a process but does not guarantee any particular outcome.
Any Data Subject who wishes to exercise any of the above-mentioned rights may do so by filing such request with the designated Data Protection Officer:Director of Institutional Compliance & Privacy
Office of Audit, Compliance & Privacy 304 Samford Hall, Auburn University, AL 36849 (334) 844-4389
Cookies
Cookies are files that many websites transfer to users' web browsers to enable the site to deliver personalized services or to provide persistent authentication. The information contained in a cookie typically includes information collected automatically by the web server and/or information provided voluntarily by the user. Auburn University's websites use persistent cookies in conjunction with a third party technology partner to analyze search engine usage and web traffic patterns. This information is used in the aggregate to monitor and enhance our web pages. It is not used to track the usage patterns of individual users. For more information see our main website Privacy Statement.
Security of Personal Data
All Personal Data and sensitive Personal Data collected or processed by Auburn University must comply with the security controls and systems and process requirements and standards set forth in Auburn University's Policies Database as they are amended from time-to-time.
Auburn University will not share your Personal Data with third parties except:
as necessary to meet one of its lawful purposes, including but not limited to, its legitimate interest, contract compliance, pursuant to consent provided by the Data Subject, or as required or authorized by law;
as necessary to protect Auburn University's interests;
with service providers acting on Auburn University's behalf who have agreed to protect the confidentiality of the Personal Data.
Data Retention
Auburn University maintains records for the time periods specified in the Public Universities of Alabama - Functional Analysis & Records Disposition Authority.
Last Updated: February 25, 2020
